For the last task this week
we switch over to CodeWorld.
Here we have given a level description
for some video game where we have Integer
coordinates that are mapped to an Integer value
indicating what to draw at that specific location.
So we have four different types of
tiles that we would like to draw and
zero indicating blank space.
And we have these four different tiles
defined here, already given to us.
And we should now
define a function that does this mapping from
these numbers to the actual images for the tile.
And then we should build a scene
that renders the whole level
from values for x and y from -10 to 10.
Okay, let's start with mapping the integer
encoding of the tiles to the actual pictures.
Once again, first we can name our input.
And now it's tempting to
just use guards and say, okay input 0 then
we're using blank if x == 1 and so on.
This works fine but it's
not the best way to do it.
Instead of using guards here, you can
write the integers directly here and
Haskell will match these and choose the correct
right-hand side depending on what input we get.
So we can just write it like this for 0
and then write aTile 1 = ... and now 1
should correspond to blocks, so we
just choose the picture for block here
aTile 2 should be water.
aTile 3 is a pearl.
And aTile 4 is air.
And then instead of the otherwise
we can use the wildcard (_).
Just say this blank and now we could merge
this zero case with the one down here.
So aTile 0 is then caught by
this case and produces blank.
Okay, so let's quickly see if this works
by using this function here in scene.
For 1 we get the block, for
2 we hopefully get water.
Yes, that's what water looks like here.
Then we have the pearl.
And air.
Okay, this works fine and if we now use 0 we
get in the default case where it's just blank.
And the same thing happens if
we, for example, choose something
way out of bounds like 11 so
we have a blank picture there.
Okay, so now how do we actually
draw all these coordinates?
So we should go from -10 to 10 on both
dimensions and evaluate the level,
check out what we have to
draw there and then draw it.
And the task requires us
to not use recursion here.
So what we do is, we use a list comprehension
because we want to evaluate the 'level' function
at some x's and y's and these x's and y's
are drawn from the range of -10 to 10.
Let's change the layout a little bit.
This will come in handy in a second.
Okay, now we have all these
red squiggly lines that
tell us that this is actually
a [Integer] and not a Picture.
But it is a list of Integers
so that's a good first step.
Now we have this 'aTile' function which
actually converts Integers into Pictures
so we call aTile on this Integer value
that we just got from the 'level' function.
And now the compiler complains that we should have
given a Picture but instead given a [Picture].
Well, we use the 'pictures' function to combine
these multiple pictures into one single Picture.
And now we evaluated the level at
each position and drawn the tile.
But they are all on top of each other,
that's not really what we wanted.
We have this huge list of tiles and
they are all in the coordinate origin.
So we need to translate them.
And the question is what values
we use to translate them?
Just x and y really.
For example, the (-10,-10) tile should go
all the way here and down here somewhere.
So we translate it by -10 and -10.
Now we have a problem though.
Because 'translated' requires Doubles
and 'level' requires Integers,
x cannot be both an Integer and a Double.
So the error occurs here because this is
inferred first to Double and then here
we try to use the x and y, that are
inferred as Double, as Integers.
Generally it's better to use non-floating
point numbers for these ranges
because they behave more nicely so
we want to actually change these.
We want to treat x and y as Integers
and convert them to Double here.
And for that we use fromIntegral x.
Same for y.
And now the compiler is happy
because this x is now an Integer.
Here we use it as an Integer to call 'level' and
here we convert it from an Integer to a Double.
Okay, so let's see what happens.
This is our level as specified over here.
And with this translation function from integers
to pictures and this layout here we get our nice
grid-based level.
And if we now change something here ...
Change what is drawn there ...
We can alter the level.
And you can play around with this and design your
own level if you want, which is a fun exercise.
Okay, so that's that for this task.
If you know that you should use a list
comprehension for it, the solution
comes really naturally.
You follow the types a bit to make
sure everything fits together.
Nothing too fancy, but the result is quite nice.